<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:series="https://publishpress.com/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Justin Bowser &#8211; Blasted Science</title>
	<atom:link href="/author/justinbowser77/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>DIY Projects Done Completely Wrong</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 04:55:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">123820757</site>	<item>
		<title>Alternative Energy: Ocean Energy</title>
		<link>/alternative-energy-ocean-energy/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=alternative-energy-ocean-energy</link>
					<comments>/alternative-energy-ocean-energy/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Justin Bowser]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 05:24:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Informational]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electricity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=324</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>This is the first of an article series on totally wacky and sometimes reasonable alternative energy sources.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/alternative-energy-ocean-energy/">Alternative Energy: Ocean Energy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blasted Science</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div style="width: 2510px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/1/10/Schneebergerhof_01.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/1/10/Schneebergerhof_01.jpg" alt="solar and wind power" width="2500" height="2500" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Alternative energy</p></div>
<p>This is the first of an article series on totally wacky and sometimes reasonable alternative energy sources. Ocean energy is one of the reasonable ones. (I&#8217;m assuming you read Blasted Science for entertainment. If you&#8217;re actually trying to learn something, you should look elsewhere. Now shut up and read my <del>chemistry essay</del> article)</p>
<p>Fossil fuels are the backbone of our energy-guzzling society. Fossil fuels are also the backbone of a dinosaur. The term &#8220;fossil fuels&#8221; refers to a category of energy sources that are nonrenewable and mostly made of dead things. Coal, natural gas, crude oil, and dinosaurs are all examples of fossil fuels. For instance, the electricity being used by the electronic device you&#8217;re using to read this article was probably generated by a dinosaur.</p>
<p>As much as it pains me type, fossil fuels are running out. If this happens, power companies will have to resort to using large employee-powered hamster wheels to generate electricity. Obviously, we can&#8217;t let this happen! Hamsters and unions would violently protest. To avoid this nightmare scenario, we need to come up with ways of powering our gadgets without damaging fossils.</p>
<h2><span style="line-height: 1.5;">Ocean Energy</span></h2>
<p>One unknown but fairly practical source of energy is our oceans. Since the Earth&#8217;s surface is around seventy percent water, you can collect it from almost anywhere and use it on a wide scale. There are three different types of ocean energy: wave energy, tidal energy, and ocean thermal energy conversion.</p>
<h2>Wave Energy</h2>
<p><a href="http://www.boem.gov/Renewable-Energy-Program/Renewable-Energy-Guide/Ocean-Wave-Energy.aspx">Wave energy</a> is produced by—you guessed it—waves. It is completely renewable, widely available, eco-friendly, and dinosaur-friendly. Produced by placing ship-like structures out in the ocean, these structures use their buoyancy to rise and fall with the waves. Then, they take the kinetic energy of the wave and convert it into electrical energy, much like the generators in the Hoover Dam. There are downsides though: it could affect the marine ecosystem, it’s dependent on wavelength, and could cause disturbances to other boats; commercial and private.</p>
<div style="width: 1610px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/c/ce/WaveDragon.JPG"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/c/ce/WaveDragon.JPG" alt="Ocean energy generator &quot;Wave Dragon&quot;" width="1600" height="1200" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text"><a href="http://www.wavedragon.net/">Wave Dragon</a></p></div>
<h2>Tidal Energy</h2>
<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tidal_power">Tidal energy</a> uses the kinetic energy of tides (not waves) and converts it into electrical energy. It’s renewable and can produce electricity on a large scale. Tides are also more predictable than waves, which probably affects something in some beneficial way. Although it follows the same principle of kinetic/electrical conversion, tidal uses a different approach. Instead of using the rising and falling of waves, it uses turbines, in similar fashion to windmills. Moving tides carry a lot of force. That, in turn, moves the turbines, which generate electricity. Although it can hurt the land, cause disturbances to boats, and chop up fish like kale in a vegan&#8217;s blender, compared to dinosaurs this option sounds positively heartwarming.</p>
<div style="width: 4282px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/e/e9/SeaGen,_Strangford,_June_2011_(02).JPG"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/e/e9/SeaGen,_Strangford,_June_2011_(02).JPG" alt="ocean energy: &quot;tide mill&quot;" width="4272" height="2848" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Tidal Energy &#8220;Tide Mill&#8221;</p></div>
<h2>Ocean Thermal Energy Conversion</h2>
<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ocean_thermal_energy_conversion">Ocean thermal energy conversion</a> (OTEC for short) is different than the others, obviously implying that it&#8217;s more useful (think Rudolph).  As the name implies, it converts the thermal energy of the ocean into electrical energy. This is how it works, the sun beams down onto the water, and as it sends energy into the ocean, it excites the water molecules, causing them to warm up. Then the machine (which looks a lot like an oil rig) takes the warm surface water and cold deep water into heat exchangers, which generate electricity. It is one of the continuously available renewable energy resources. It can potentially generate up to 88,000 terrawatt-hours/yr of power. There are two types of OTEC: open- or closed-cycle. Closed-cycle generators use refrigerant fluids, such as ammonia. These fluids have low boiling points and that makes them suitable for powering the generator. Open-cycle generators use sea water vapor to work as the fluid instead of the refrigerants.</p>
<div style="width: 410px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/3/37/Otec_produkty-2_(English).png"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/3/37/Otec_produkty-2_(English).png" alt="Ocean thermal energy conversion diagram" width="400" height="303" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">OTEC Diagram</p></div>
<p>I think that Ocean energy could be the next big source of energy. It seems practical even though it may have some difficulties connected to it. Ocean energy can and will bring energy to everybody and everything. Say goodbye to dinosaurs. Welcome to the Future.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/alternative-energy-ocean-energy/">Alternative Energy: Ocean Energy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blasted Science</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/alternative-energy-ocean-energy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">324</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tesla Coils</title>
		<link>/tesla-coils/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=tesla-coils</link>
					<comments>/tesla-coils/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Justin Bowser]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2016 23:40:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[High Voltage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dangerous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electronics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[high voltage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla coil]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=192</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Building one is a big accomplishment in the DIY electronics world. It takes lots of time and effort. Let's try to remove those requirements.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/tesla-coils/">Tesla Coils</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blasted Science</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: left;">You&#8217;ve probably heard about Tesla coils. Heck, you&#8217;ve probably played with one. You can even <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B008PO5QKW/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=B008PO5QKW&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=blastscien-20&amp;linkId=TUFR6NMRKNEE3NNX" rel="nofollow">get a little one for under $15</a>. However, it&#8217;s less than likely that you&#8217;ve considered building one. <span id="more-192"></span>That would take hard work, right? It would take too long to learn how they work and find all of the parts. Right?</p>
<h3 style="text-align: center;">Wrong.</h3>
<p>Actually, you&#8217;re probably right. Tesla coil aren&#8217;t easy. Building one is a big accomplishment in the DIY electronics world. It takes lots of time and effort. Let&#8217;s try to remove those requirements with a quick crash course:</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Tesla coils are one of the many inventions invented by Nikola Tesla. The Coils produces high-voltage, high frequency alternating-current electricity. They consists of two main parts: a primary coil, and a secondary coil. In fact, &#8220;Tesla&#8221; is actually Latin for &#8220;contains a primary and secondary coil.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">By far the most difficult part of building one is finding a power source. These bad boys take some serious juice to operate. Once the power is connected the primary capacitor starts charging. As the capacitor fills up with electricity, that it lowers the air resistance of the spark. Then is leaves the capacitor and through the primary coil. As it does that it creates an electromagnetic field. Then again the immense charge, overloads and makes the magnetic field collapse in on itself. Generating an electric current in the secondary coil. The volts go through the air between the two coils creating a spark. It bounces back and forth through the coils, charging the secondary coil, and capacitor. Then it overloads and a spark breaks from the coil in a big burst of current.</span></p>
<div style="width: 312px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="http://www.tb3.net/tesla/hugecoil/animations/HC200.gif"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="" src="http://www.tb3.net/tesla/hugecoil/animations/HC200.gif" alt="Tesla Coil Gif" width="302" height="264" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Source: <a href="http://www.tb3.net/tesla/hugecoil/animations/HC200.gif">tb3.net</a></p></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tesla coils are very exciting and can be made fairly easily with a few feet of copper wire, and some capacitors. here’s a schematic for you smart folks:<a href="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/2/24/Tesla_coil_4.svg/2000px-Tesla_coil_4.svg.png"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter" src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/2/24/Tesla_coil_4.svg/2000px-Tesla_coil_4.svg.png" alt="Tesla Coil Schematic" width="548" height="352" /></a></span></p>
<p>Essentially, all they require is:</p>
<ul>
<li>A high voltage power supply.</li>
<li>A bunch of capacitors.</li>
<li>A freaking TON of copper wire wound into a coil.</li>
</ul>
<p>That&#8217;s all there is to it. They&#8217;re simpler than most people think. In fact, it&#8217;s probably harder to wind the wire into a coil than it is to find and assemble all the parts. The hardest part is finding a high voltage DC power supply. They cost hundreds of dollars, or you can just make your own for much cheaper. We&#8217;ll have a tutorial on the details at some point.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Plenty of people on the internet have made Tesla coils, but <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/11834044@N04/9030518160">this is one of our favorites</a>. Sam Freeman&#8217;s coil requires beer bottles. This redneck nerd gets the official Blasted Science Seal of Approval.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Let&#8217;s assume for a moment that you have a competed Tesla coil. Why stop there? Here are some things you can do to it to make it even better. </span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">A plasma gun</span></h3>
<div style="width: 582px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="http://www.rmcybernetics.com/images/main/eng/plasma-gun-2-open.jpg"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="" src="http://www.rmcybernetics.com/images/main/eng/plasma-gun-2-open.jpg" alt="Tesla Coil Gun" width="572" height="294" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Source: <a href="http://www.rmcybernetics.com/projects/DIY_Devices/plasma-gun-2.htm">RM Cybernetics</a></p></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3 style="text-align: center;">Car anti-theft system</h3>
<div style="width: 582px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="http://tesladownunder.com/Tesladownunder's%20Car%20Theft%20Pevention%201000.jpg"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="" src="http://tesladownunder.com/Tesladownunder's%20Car%20Theft%20Pevention%201000.jpg" alt="Tesla Coil Car Theft Prevention" width="572" height="381" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Source: <a href="http://tesladownunder.com/Tesladownunder's%20Car%20Theft%20Pevention%201000.jpg">Tesla Down Under</a></p></div>
<h3 style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Music</span></h3>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='800' height='480' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/L5E4NiP4hpM?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;autohide=2&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;'></iframe></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We&#8217;re ashamed to admit that we haven&#8217;t made our own Tesla coil yet, but we definitely will at some point. And when we do, we&#8217;ll have a tutorial detailing exactly how to do it with household parts. But if that sounds like too much work, you can buy a small one for just a few dollars. We&#8217;ve personally tested this one from Amazon. It&#8217;s a very good miniature plasma globe, which, as you may have guessed, is just a Tesla coil in a plastic globe. Definitely check this one out.<br />
</span></p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" style="width: 120px; height: 240px;" src="//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ac&amp;ref=tf_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=blastscien-20&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;region=US&amp;placement=B008PO5QKW&amp;asins=B008PO5QKW&amp;linkId=VPXDRTOJSUU5W2W2&amp;show_border=true&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=true" width="300" height="150" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no">&nbsp;</p>
<p></iframe></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/tesla-coils/">Tesla Coils</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blasted Science</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/tesla-coils/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">192</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!--
Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: https://www.boldgrid.com/w3-total-cache/

Page Caching using disk: enhanced (Requested URI contains query) 

Served from: blastedscience.com @ 2023-08-21 21:45:39 by W3 Total Cache
-->