<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:series="https://publishpress.com/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>current &#8211; Blasted Science</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/current/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>DIY Projects Done Completely Wrong</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 15:09:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">123820757</site>	<item>
		<title>Possible Foreshadowing? A Failed Jacob&#8217;s Ladder Experiment</title>
		<link>/possible-foreshadowing-failed-jacobs-ladder-experiment/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=possible-foreshadowing-failed-jacobs-ladder-experiment</link>
					<comments>/possible-foreshadowing-failed-jacobs-ladder-experiment/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Josh Moody]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 15:02:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Electricity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[High Voltage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Informational]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[current]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[danger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dangerous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[death]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electricity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electronics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[high voltage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[informational]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[safety]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[voltage]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=650</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>A young boy, not unlike the members of Blasted Science, built a Jacob's Ladder in his garage. Unfortunately, he is now dead.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/possible-foreshadowing-failed-jacobs-ladder-experiment/">Possible Foreshadowing? A Failed Jacob&#8217;s Ladder Experiment</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blasted Science</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-693" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/imminent-death-finaler-1024x640.png" alt="Imminent Death" width="800" height="500" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/imminent-death-finaler-1024x640.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/02/imminent-death-finaler-300x188.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/02/imminent-death-finaler-400x250.png 400w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/02/imminent-death-finaler.png 1152w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /></h3>
<h3><strong>Late Condolences to a Brother in Arms</strong></h3>
<p><a href="https://mic.com/articles/141570/teen-morgan-wojciechowski-dies-in-youtube-jacobs-ladder-science-experiment#.5AuBED6la">Turns out we aren&#8217;t the only idiots in the world.</a> Some other guy decided to copy us and make a Jacob&#8217;s ladder. Unlike us, though, they were unable to keep themselves safe. They are no longer with us. Actually, they haven&#8217;t been with us for almost a year now. We didn&#8217;t get the message until recently.</p>
<h3><strong>Homemade Jacob&#8217;s Ladder</strong></h3>
<p>A young boy, not unlike the members of Blasted Science, built a Jacob&#8217;s Ladder in his garage, just like we did. Tragically, he was found dead by his parents.</p>
<blockquote>
<p class="">A 15-year-old boy in Ohio electrocuted himself while attempting a science experiment he saw on YouTube, <i><a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/us-ohio-electrocution-idUSKCN0XH29C">Reuters</a></i> reported.</p>
<p class="p1">The teenager, Morgan Wojciechowski, tried to conduct a high-voltage experiment, called <a href="http://newyork.cbslocal.com/2016/04/20/teen-electrocuted-youtube/">Jacob&#8217;s Ladder</a>, in the garage of his home in northern Ohio. Wojciechowski&#8217;s parents found him there on Tuesday, <a href="http://abcnews.go.com/US/wireStory/ohio-boy-electrocuted-conducting-youtube-experiment-38537056">ABC News</a> reported, and emergency crews took him to the hospital, where he was pronounced dead.</p>
<p class="p1"><a href="https://mic.com/articles/141570/teen-morgan-wojciechowski-dies-in-youtube-jacobs-ladder-science-experiment#.5CkrL1SIC">Source</a></p>
</blockquote>
<h3><strong>Cause of Death</strong></h3>
<p>The article suggests that the reason he died was because many online Jacob&#8217;s Ladder tutorials don&#8217;t have any warning about how dangerous it is:</p>
<blockquote><p>It&#8217;s easy to find a Jacob&#8217;s Ladder tutorial on the internet, and it might not tell you you can die from making it.</p></blockquote>
<p>That&#8217;s a pretty awful thing for people to do. How could they just ignore the danger to their viewer&#8217;s lives? That&#8217;s downright sinister. A big problem for many tutorials is that the author can unintentionally assume that the viewer already knows how dangerous electrical experiments are.</p>
<p>(Editor&#8217;s note: contrary to popular belief, we aren&#8217;t guilty of this whatsoever; <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=49WSXFQVTCI&amp;t=5m12s">we know how dangerous Jacob&#8217;s Ladders are,</a> but <em>choose</em> to ignore it. Because we&#8217;re smart, y&#8217;all.)</p>
<h3><strong>The Lesson</strong></h3>
<p>Don&#8217;t be a dumb! Compared to the one in the article, our Jacob&#8217;s Ladder had double the voltage and we probably took less precautions. There&#8217;s also no chance that we&#8217;re more intelligent than our deceased compadre. How did we survive? The answer is simply the combination of our two best traits: sheer luck and incredibly thick, resistive skin.</p>
<div id="attachment_737" style="width: 810px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-737" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-737" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/wp-1487781213609-1024x576.jpg" alt="Jacob's Ladder" width="800" height="450" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/wp-1487781213609-1024x576.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/02/wp-1487781213609-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/02/wp-1487781213609-320x180.jpg 320w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/02/wp-1487781213609-400x225.jpg 400w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/02/wp-1487781213609.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /><p id="caption-attachment-737" class="wp-caption-text">Blasted Science&#8217;s first attempt at a Jacob&#8217;s Ladder.</p></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/possible-foreshadowing-failed-jacobs-ladder-experiment/">Possible Foreshadowing? A Failed Jacob&#8217;s Ladder Experiment</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blasted Science</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/possible-foreshadowing-failed-jacobs-ladder-experiment/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">650</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Video: Blasted Science Documentary</title>
		<link>/new-video-blasted-science-documentary-dangerous-diy-projects/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=new-video-blasted-science-documentary-dangerous-diy-projects</link>
					<comments>/new-video-blasted-science-documentary-dangerous-diy-projects/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Josh Moody]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2017 03:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Electricity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[High Voltage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Informational]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blowtorch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[current]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[danger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dangerous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[death]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electricity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electronics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lasers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[low-cost]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[propane torch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[styrofoam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[update]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[voltage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weapons]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=618</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Blasted Science's first video! Spoiler warning: it's dangerous.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/new-video-blasted-science-documentary-dangerous-diy-projects/">New Video: Blasted Science Documentary</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blasted Science</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Blasted Science&#8217;s first video! This is an introduction into what we do at Blasted Science. Spoiler warning: it&#8217;s dangerous. Stay tuned for more videos about all of the projects mentioned in this video!</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/49WSXFQVTCI" width="560" height="314" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>This update is a couple months late. We noticed.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/new-video-blasted-science-documentary-dangerous-diy-projects/">New Video: Blasted Science Documentary</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blasted Science</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/new-video-blasted-science-documentary-dangerous-diy-projects/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">618</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Top 5 More Household Items to Turn into Weapons</title>
		<link>/top-5-more-household-items-to-turn-into-weapons/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=top-5-more-household-items-to-turn-into-weapons</link>
					<comments>/top-5-more-household-items-to-turn-into-weapons/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Josh Moody]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2016 17:04:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Informational]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top 5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blowtorch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[current]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[danger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dangerous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electricity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electronics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flamethrower]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[low-cost]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top 5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weapons]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=487</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>We don&#8217;t feel like we covered everything last time. Here are five more dangerous tools you can make from ordinary household items. Poke your eye out, kid. 5. Spaghetti A thermic lance is a heavy-duty demolition tool that burns steel alloys and aluminum in pressurized oxygen to create temperatures hot enough to cut… anything, really. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/top-5-more-household-items-to-turn-into-weapons/">Top 5 More Household Items to Turn into Weapons</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blasted Science</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We don&#8217;t feel like we covered everything last time. Here are five more dangerous tools you can make from ordinary household items. Poke your eye out, kid.</p>
<p><span id="more-487"></span></p>
<h3><b>5. Spaghetti</b></h3>
<p>A thermic lance is a heavy-duty demolition tool that burns steel alloys and aluminum in pressurized oxygen to create temperatures hot enough to cut… anything, really. Instead of burning steel, this do-it-yourself version uses spaghetti as fuel.</p>
<p>Spaghetti may not seem particularly flammable, but with pure oxygen just about everything becomes a pyromaniac’s dream. With just an oxygen tank, aluminum foil, and a small handful of spaghetti, you can make a thermic lance that burns hot enough to melt through concrete.</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/-sEdHh1Xjb0" width="560" height="314" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>Thermic lances are used in construction and demolition to cut large pieces of steel. This homemade version can get hot enough to melt metal. All you have to do is hook up one side of a small hose to an oxygen tank and attach a small amount of spaghetti wrapped in aluminum foil to the other. Igniting the spaghetti in the oxygen-rich tube produces a crazy-hot flame, creating the cheapest steel-melting lance you&#8217;ll ever see.</p>
<p>It is worth noting that Blasted Science has constructed their own thermic lance. However, ours never runs out of oxygen. Instead of a tank, we hooked it up to an oxygen generator for longer burning.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-496" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/Thermic-Lance-1.gif" alt="Thermic Lance" width="360" height="360" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><b>4. Ammonia</b></p>
<p>Ammonia itself can be dangerous (inhalation not recommended), but when combined with iodine, the extremely volatile explosive Nitrogen Triiodide is formed. Touching it with just about anything is enough to make it explode.</p>
<p>All you need is ammonium hydroxide, easily purchased as a household cleaner, and iodine crystals, easily purchased online. Simply dissolve the iodine crystals in the ammonium hydroxide and wait a few hours. Pour the resulting liquid over filter paper to collect the explosive. Be careful: even though the compound is more stable while in solution, it can still potentially explode while dissolved.</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/0nOikC5W3U8" width="560" height="314" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>Nitrogen Triiodide has no practical use, due to its extreme sensitivity to friction, but it can certainly be entertaining. Be extremely careful with these crystals; the slightest touch and you can kiss your fingers goodbye. It’s recommended that you start small, and work your way up to bigger amounts once you know what you’re doing.</p>
<p>Blasted Science attempted to make Nitrogren Triiodide, but our iodine samples weren&#8217;t nearly pure enough for it to work.  Sticking live wires into a bottle filled with iodized salt water probably wasn&#8217;t the best way to obtain iodine.</p>
<h3><b>3. Etch-a-Sketch</b></h3>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/etch-a-sketch.jpg"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-542 size-full" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/etch-a-sketch-e1479857567215.jpg" alt="Etch a Sketch" width="512" height="512" /></a></p>
<p>This common toy is loaded with powdered aluminum. Aluminum, sadly, doesn&#8217;t burn. Unless it&#8217;s combined with rust, that is.</p>
<p>Mixing powdered aluminum and iron oxide (rust) in the correct ratio, three parts iron oxide to one part aluminum, creates thermite. Thermite isn&#8217;t explosive, but burns at insanely high temperatures and produces iron. However, it also requires insanely high temperatures to ignite; a normal flame won’t do it. Using a sparkler is an easy way to get it started. Never ignite thermite near yourself; it spews molten metal all over the place. You don’t want to be anywhere near it once it’s lit.</p>
<p>After the time of writing (this list has been in limbo for a long time), Grant Thompson and Cody&#8217;s Lab successfully created thermite from an Etch-a-Sketch. The video from Cody&#8217;s Lab goes into greater detail on their project.</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/Mbk7ijNQlMc" width="560" height="314" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>Thermite burns at well above 4,000° Fahrenheit: hot enough to melt through things not usually considered meltable, such as dirt. Good luck finding a container that can hold it. Most commonly, ceramic containers are used, such as flowerpots. Surprisingly, it is 100% legal to own and use. Have fun.</p>
<h3><b>2. Drain Cleaner</b></h3>
<p>Drain cleaner, aluminum foil, and a pop bottle are used to make what is called a “Drano bomb.” Combining drain cleaner (sodium hydroxide) and aluminum foil produces hydrogen gas. If the reaction occurs in a sealed bottle, the pressure will increase until the bottle explodes.</p>
<p>Using drain cleaner to make bottle bombs can be very dangerous. The explosion can cause chemical burns and the loss of fingers. For this device in particular, please be mature. These bombs are often left in people’s yards and mailboxes, and can cause severe damage to people and property. Be extremely careful with explosives and never use them to harm anyone or anything.</p>
<p>Alternatively, try stretching a balloon over the mouth of the bottle. The balloon will fill with hydrogen gas, which is lighter than helium and extremely flammable. Try lighting the balloon with a match, even a small balloon will make a sizeable explosion. You&#8217;ll definitely want to wear thick gloves while lighting it.</p>
<div id="attachment_544" style="width: 249px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/Drano.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-544" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-544 size-medium" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/Drano-239x300.jpg" alt="Drano Balloon" width="239" height="300" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-544" class="wp-caption-text">Blasted Science&#8217;s hydrogen bomb in the making</p></div>
<p>Blasted Science can confirm that this works very well. Unfortunately, our video has become corrupted, and our only evidence is the single photograph above.</p>
<h3><b>1. Lantern Battery</b></h3>
<p>Using a power supply built from microwave oven transformers, the carbon rods in lantern batteries happen to work perfectly as electrodes in a miniature electric arc furnace hot enough to turn metal and rocks into molten goop.</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/VTzKIs19eZE" width="560" height="314" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>The entire process is detailed by Grant Thompson in one of his most dangerous DIY projects to date. This project is a bit more complicated than the rest: you’ll need to use the transformers from a pair of microwaves to convert the electricity from your house into a current capable of forming an arc. But the effort is well worth it. With a couple of microwaves, pliers, carbon rods, and a block of firebrick, you can make a forge capable of melting just about everything imaginable.</p>
<p>However, all that power comes at the price of serious danger. This is easily the most dangerous item on this list. You’ll be dealing with electricity, extremely high temperatures, toxic fumes, and molten metal. Because of this, take appropriate safety measures. This project is not for the faint of heart.</p>
<p>Once again, Blasted Science has constructed their own version of this. However, it deserves more than just a mention in a list. Expect more information on our arc furnace in the future.</p>
<div id="attachment_548" style="width: 810px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/Screenshot_20161126-095816.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-548" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-548" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/Screenshot_20161126-095816-1024x576.png" alt="Arc Furnace" width="800" height="450" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-548" class="wp-caption-text">Just to prove we aren&#8217;t making this up</p></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/top-5-more-household-items-to-turn-into-weapons/">Top 5 More Household Items to Turn into Weapons</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blasted Science</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/top-5-more-household-items-to-turn-into-weapons/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		
		<series:name><![CDATA[Household Weapons]]></series:name>
<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">487</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Avoid Being Killed by Electricity</title>
		<link>/how-to-avoid-being-killed-by-electricity/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=how-to-avoid-being-killed-by-electricity</link>
					<comments>/how-to-avoid-being-killed-by-electricity/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Josh Moody]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2016 05:47:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[High Voltage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[current]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[death]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electricity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[safety]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tutorial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[voltage]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=210</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>It’s a good idea to know what you’re getting into. When is electricity dangerous?</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-to-avoid-being-killed-by-electricity/">How to Avoid Being Killed by Electricity</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blasted Science</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;">Electricity is Dangerous</h2>
<p>Electricity is really cool. It can also be extremely dangerous. Obviously, this shouldn’t discourage you from playing with high-powered electrical devices. It’s a good idea to know what you’re getting into, though. When is electricity dangerous?</p>
<p><span id="more-210"></span></p>
<p>You could just go read <a href="https://www.lanl.gov/safety/electrical/docs/elec_hazard_awareness_study_guide.pdf#page=8">this PDF</a>, but should you really trust the government with your life? Blasted Science has plenty of experience with electricity. Trust us.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: center;">How Much is Lethal?</h3>
<p>It takes a <a href="http://gizmodo.com/5262971/giz-explains-how-electrocution-really-kills-you">surprisingly small amount</a> of electricity to kill you. According to <a href="http://adamsavage.com/">Adam Savage</a>, all it takes is 7 milliamps for three seconds. That’s tiny. An LED would barely light up with that amount of current. And since the internal resistance of the human body is about <a href="http://eplasty.com/index.php?option=com_content&amp;view=article&amp;id=345&amp;catid=170:volume-09-eplasty-2009">300 ohms</a>, it would only require 2.1 volts to kill. That&#8217;s only slightly more than a AA battery.</p>
<p>Fortunately, our bodies have one big protection to electricity: skin. Dry skin has a resistance of <a href="http://eplasty.com/index.php?option=com_content&amp;view=article&amp;id=345&amp;catid=170:volume-09-eplasty-2009">100,000 ohms to 600,000 ohms</a>. You might think this means that you’d need to be shocked with at least 3430 volts before your life is at risk, but it&#8217;s not that simple.</p>
<p>The above calculation applies only to dry skin. Wet skin is much more conductive. Voltages as low as 50 volts can be dangerous when your skin is wet.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: center;">Breakdown Voltage</h3>
<p>At high voltages, skin loses most of its resistance and becomes much more conductive. As <a href="http://At/ 500 V or more, high resistance in the outer layer of the skin breaks down.3 This lowers the body's resistance to current flow greatly. The result is an increase in the amount of current that flows with any given voltage. Areas of skin breakdown are sometimes pinhead-sized wounds that can be easily overlooked. They are often a sign that a large amount of current could enter the body. This current can be expected to result in deep tissue injury to muscles, nerves, and other structures. This is one reason why there is often significant deep tissue injury little in the way of skin burns with high-voltage injuries.">eplasty.com</a> puts it,</p>
<blockquote><p>At 500 V or more, high resistance in the outer layer of the skin breaks down. This lowers the body&#8217;s resistance to current flow greatly. The result is an increase in the amount of current that flows with any given voltage. Areas of skin breakdown are sometimes pinhead-sized wounds that can be easily overlooked. They are often a sign that a large amount of current could enter the body. This current can be expected to result in deep tissue injury to muscles, nerves, and other structures. This is one reason why there is often significant deep tissue injury little in the way of skin burns with high-voltage injuries.</p></blockquote>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Summary</h2>
<p>In summary, the danger of electricity is highly variable. The best option is to play it safe. Exercise caution with any moderate to high voltage source. We&#8217;ve only scratched the surface of electrical dangers. There are many other factors that are beyond the scope of this article.</p>
<p>Does this mean you should avoid electricity at all costs? Of course not! Just don&#8217;t be stupid. At least, not as stupid as we are. Blasted Science has made some incredibly poor decisions with electricity in the past. It&#8217;s remarkable that we&#8217;re all still alive. Please don&#8217;t follow our example.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-to-avoid-being-killed-by-electricity/">How to Avoid Being Killed by Electricity</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blasted Science</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/how-to-avoid-being-killed-by-electricity/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">210</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!--
Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: https://www.boldgrid.com/w3-total-cache/

Page Caching using disk: enhanced (Requested URI contains query) 

Served from: blastedscience.com @ 2023-08-21 21:45:22 by W3 Total Cache
-->