<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:series="https://publishpress.com/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Bastian Hulse &#8211; Blasted Science</title>
	<atom:link href="/author/buddhabash/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>DIY Projects Done Completely Wrong</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 15:35:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">123820757</site>	<item>
		<title>Nuclear Energy &#8211; Why Not?</title>
		<link>/nuclear-energy-not/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=nuclear-energy-not</link>
					<comments>/nuclear-energy-not/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Bastian Hulse]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 20:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Electricity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Informational]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electricity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[informational]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=719</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Too many people are whining about the use of nuclear power. Before you bag on it you should actually learn how it works.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/nuclear-energy-not/">Nuclear Energy &#8211; Why Not?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blasted Science</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Too many people hear the word nuclear and immediately think that whatever it is used for is bad, but what about power plants?</span></p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="alignnone wp-image-721" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/Chooz_Nuclear_Power_Plant-9361-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="722" height="406" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/Chooz_Nuclear_Power_Plant-9361-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/02/Chooz_Nuclear_Power_Plant-9361-320x180.jpg 320w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/02/Chooz_Nuclear_Power_Plant-9361-400x225.jpg 400w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/02/Chooz_Nuclear_Power_Plant-9361.jpg 800w" sizes="(max-width: 722px) 100vw, 722px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We have been hearing way too much about alternative energy sources and random crappy sources that are not efficient at all. We already have a great source, but a few experiences that make us not want to touch it. This great source is nuclear energy.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Like we said earlier you probably don’t like the sound of it, but the truth is nuclear energy is the bomb! Pun very intended. All jokes aside, nuclear energy is cleaner, safer, and more efficient than most people think. People terrified of the unknown. So let&#8217;s learn some things to make it known.</span></p>
<h3><strong>How does it work?</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nuclear energy is created through a process called nuclear fission. Nuclear fission is just a fancy word for splitting apart a nuclear atom to acquire the desired superpower. Well half of that is true, I’ll let you decide which half. This energy is in the form of heat which warms up some liquid, Blasted Science prefers Dr. Pepper, but we are only humble rocket scientists. When the Dr. Pepper is hot enough it will start making bubbles and will steam. It must be approximately 212 degrees Fahrenheit or if you live any other place but the United States 100 degrees Celsius. The best way to tell the temperature is to dive straight in it and time how long it takes to burn the flesh. Once you are nice and crispy then you know it is ready.</span></p>
<h3><strong>Safety Stuffs</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It is safe, trust us. Don’t question only obey. There are so many safety precautions that we don’t know where to start. So we won’t start. Instead we will loosely quote what pulled up on Google “Nuclear power is safe and continuing to get safer, so stop being a baby you’re fine.” That’s what Google said, so if you don’t trust us then trust them.</span></p>
<h3><strong>Conclusion</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We are constantly improving as a species. What is the point in improving barbaric ways of making energy if we could just switch to one that is way better? Blasted Science is not here to tell you that you are wrong, unless of course you are, but we do want to inform you. We think you should form your own opinion, and as long as it is the same as ours you should voice it. </span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/nuclear-energy-not/">Nuclear Energy &#8211; Why Not?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blasted Science</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/nuclear-energy-not/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">719</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Build Your Own Tablet</title>
		<link>/the-tablet-build-for-you/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-tablet-build-for-you</link>
					<comments>/the-tablet-build-for-you/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Bastian Hulse]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 16:49:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electronics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[low-cost]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tablet]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=181</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Having trouble finding a good tablet? Unfortunately, there are none. You'll have to make your own.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/the-tablet-build-for-you/">Build Your Own Tablet</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blasted Science</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;">Build Your Own Tablet</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Everyone always has a complaint about their iPad or, for that matter, any other tablet (we just prefer to roast the iPad in particular). Having trouble finding a good tablet? Trick question, there are none. You&#8217;ll have to make your own. Before you even take another step </span><b>this will cost money</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">. We know this breaks our own rules, but it&#8217;s unavoidable. Sadly, even Blasted Science can’t build a good tablet with parts found in a dumpster.</span></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-263" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/tablet-812708_960_720.png" alt="Tablet Cartoon" width="851" height="720" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/tablet-812708_960_720.png 851w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/tablet-812708_960_720-300x254.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/tablet-812708_960_720-400x338.png 400w" sizes="(max-width: 851px) 100vw, 851px" />Being the master of electronics and engineering that we are we decided we should share our knowledge and wisdom with those of you at home who may not be so gifted. That doesn&#8217;t mean you; you must be smart because you&#8217;re reading this. Just tell everyone you know that they do not have the knowledge of the all-powerful Blasted Science to help them along the journey of life. we have done the research and we know we can make the most powerful tablet you have ever seen. We have decided that the best way to do this is a step by step process, so here it goes.</p>
<ol>
<li>Do some research. It is important to have a good idea of what you want. Find a tablet that you would want and absorb all of the knowledge from the reviews. The details and specs are useless only go to reviews, preferably reviews written by people who have not bought the product.</li>
<li>Buy it. To make the tablet that fits you you will have to test it out and see what you like. While the reviews may be a very good source you are better. Test it out for a month all the while making a list of the things you do and don&#8217;t like.</li>
<li>Destroy it. You can&#8217;t be tethered to these Earthly objects when going through the process of engineering. I recommend meditation to get the clear mind that is necessary when destroying to rebuild. The destruction process is really important. You must open it up take out all the electronics in the case then use a sledgehammer to gently destroy it. Keep the case it will be important later.</li>
<li>Buy a new one. Now that you have that list of things you do and do not like buy one that fits those criteria. Once you have one that you know you like move on to the next step.</li>
<li>Take out the insides. We are still making our own.</li>
<li>Get the case out from earlier. Get the case and stuff the electronics from your new one in the old one. If it doesn&#8217;t fit then just saw off one side, it&#8217;ll probably still work.</li>
<li>Clickbait. Take out your 1000 DEGREE GLOWING KNIFE and slice the second tablet&#8217;s casing. YOU WON&#8217;T BELIEVE WHAT HAPPENS NEXT, ONLY 3% OF PEOPLE CAN SEE THE FUMES THAT IT EMITS! DO THE FUMES CONTRIBUTE TO GLOBAL WARMING??????</li>
<li>ENJOY! You are so welcome for the new and improved tablet.</li>
</ol>
<p>We at Blasted Science accept tips, and welcome you to contact us and we will give you the opportunity to donate to us.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/the-tablet-build-for-you/">Build Your Own Tablet</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Blasted Science</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/the-tablet-build-for-you/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">181</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!--
Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: https://www.boldgrid.com/w3-total-cache/

Page Caching using disk: enhanced (Requested URI contains query) 

Served from: blastedscience.com @ 2023-08-21 21:45:25 by W3 Total Cache
-->